Thomas James Pain

07872 842 130, hello@tompa.in, https://tompa.in, https://github.com/TJPain

OVERVIEW:

I am a back-end Software Engineer at Midnite, an esports gambling scale-up, working in the Growth Engineering Team to build products for user acquisition and retention with Python and Flask. I am also heavily involved in building internal tools for our Trading Team. Prior to Midnite, I spent five years building a travel start-up where I was responsible for technology (Python, Django, Vue, JavaScript, and AWS) and product.

I am also finishing the research project for my part-time MSc in Computer Science with Artificial Intelligence. For this, I am building a deep learning model for programmatic high-frequency trading of the EUR/USD currency pair. This is built with Python and Tensorflow and runs on AWS with real-time data.

CAREER HISTORY:

Midnite - Software Engineer (back-end)

May 2023 - to date

Midnite is post-series A (\$16m in 2022) esport and sport betting platform with a focus on user experience. It presents technical challenges given its large volumes of live, risk-adjusted data and operations in 11 highly regulated countries with two brands, and multiple languages and currencies. Initially hired in a full-stack role (Python, Flask, Vue, TypeScript, SQL, and AWS), I transitioned to a back-end role within the Growth team.

- Worked in a small team to build our new casino and virtuals products from scratch, defining API contracts with client teams, building cloud-native APIs, and constructing backend logic to support these products.
 Developed high-capacity services for real-time data transactions, prioritising reliability and responsiveness.
- Full stack development for new welcome and sign-up bonus products to improve customer acquisition
- Engineered an algorithm for dynamic pricing adjustments based on risk assessment and bet volumes
- Built a prize allocation service for a free-to-play game, factoring in users' predicted LTV, recent betting history, and reward accumulation to boost engagement via statistically driven prize selection

Packed – Co-Founder and Software Engineer (full stack)

March 2017 - March 2022

Packed provided a marketplace of trusted and reliable holidays for groups. Pre-covid sales were up to £230k per month, however, covid put the company into a financially difficult position and we decided to close.

- Over 2,600 customers and £2.3m in sales
- Featured in The Times, the Evening Standard, the Metro and Condé Nast
- Built the MVP product using Python, Django, GraphQL, Vue with Vue Apollo, and AWS
- Managed three overseas contract developers, a contract designer and a mobile app development agency
- Designed and launched a React Native app with over 10,000 users across iOS and Android
- Responsible for the analytics stack and technical SEO, growing organic traffic to >10k users per month

True - Senior Associate

December 2016 - August 2017

I worked closely with US and European tier-1 venture capital funds to help them strengthen the boards of their portfolio investments and regularly helped US technology companies scale into EMEA. The role blended long consultation periods with the delivery of high-profile executive search placements across board-level functions (predominantly CTO, CPO, and CMO) in all technology verticals.

Oliver James Associates – Associate Director, Design & Development, Digital and Marketing Teams January 2015 - December 2016

I was approached by OJA to establish a Digital and Technology desk. On the back of strong sales and bottom-line performance, I started Design and Marketing teams which I managed concurrently. I was promoted three times in two years and managed a team of 14 people.

Outgoing - Product Manager

May 2011 - September 2013

I was employed in a sales role but was quickly promoted to Product Manager for the Ski division where I was responsible for the department's financial performance, delivering all aspects of the passenger experience, managing six full-time staff and up to 110 seasonal staff. Increased passenger numbers from 1,600 in 2010/11 to almost 15,000 passengers in 2012/13, transforming financial performance from a small loss to a net profit of £280,000 for the 2012/13 season.

Other roles:

- Sisu Capital Ltd Intern, Distressed Debt and Operations (December 2007 February 2008) internship at a distressed debt hedge fund
- **3D Currency Management Intern** (September 2007 October 2007) internship at a hedge fund trading securitised debt in the FX market
- Sigma Wealth Management Intern and continued part-time work (July 2007 August 2009) developed a model to track fund-based renewal, researched investment opportunities and assisted with report writing and due diligence

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS:

2020-2023: University of York – MSc Computer Science with Artificial Intelligence

- Current grade average: 75.5% (distinction) with only the research project remaining
- Modules: Al and Machine Learning, Applied Al, Algorithms and Data Structures, Advanced Programming, Big Data Analytics, Computer Architecture and Operating Systems, Computer and Mobile Networks, Software Engineering, and an Al-based research project. All modules are Java or Python based.
- Building a deep learning model for programmatic high-frequency Forex trading for my research project

2020-2021: Harvard University - HarvardX CS50 Computer Science & CS50W Computer Science for Web Programming

A 6-month course covering Python, JavaScript, SQL and frameworks like Django and React

2016: University of Pennsylvania, The Wharton Business School – Business Strategy & Entrepreneurship

Part of the Wharton MBA, this is a six-month assessed remote learning course

2008-2009: Durham University - MSc Finance and Investment - Merit

2005-2008: Durham University – BA (Hons) Accounting and Finance – 2:1

Other qualifications:

- Udacity Python Nanodegree
- Microsoft Azure Al Fundamentals